[Music]
hi my name is Stephan bow and for the
next few minutes I'm going to take you
through some of the changes that we've
done to the open in vs code and GitHub
projects from the last release you might
remember that we have added the ability
to explore fields and pages from vs code
using the pH inspector you also might
remember that in the help and support
page you can now ATT ATT a debugger to
this current session this is the
foundation for the work we've done by
connecting vs code and GitHub and
extensions in business Central for this
release so let's consider the scenario
where I have a Rewards app I want to
look at so I'll go here and look at the
rewards app Let's see we have some
rewards
here I can see the list of rewards we
have here and I can create a new one and
I found this card page to be a bit
annoying because there is a description
field that is mandatory so I want to
change this so I can go here to the help
and
support and to The Trusted page
inspector there we go and from here I
can insect this page to figure out where
the different fields come from in this
case I can see that the only extension
that is in this page is the Loyalty
Rewards demo so I'll need to look at
this one if I go to the extension
management page I can find the app let's
see if we can find it
it is here the app is right here but lo
and behold I do not have access to the
source so the resource protection
policies for this app does not allow me
to download a copy of the source from
this app however if I go into the
details of this app there's a new
section below here called Source control
details here I can see the GitHub repo
where this comes from and I can see the
commit ID that is associated with the
build of this app so if if I have access
to this GitHub repo I can now see the
source from exactly the time where this
app was
built and with this new action on the
extension management page you can now
also open the source in vs code so I'm
going to click that let's see what
happens so the first thing that vs code
is going to ask me is whether I want to
open an existing repository or I want to
clone it since I haven't done this
before on my machine I'm going to clone
it and it's going to Gest me a folder
the folder here is the project folder
I'm going to use that one and now it's
going to start cloning the the
repository from the information that was
in the application that we saw in the
extension management page the next thing
that the vs code is going to ask me is
if I want to open a specific Branch I
could open the branch where um this
specific uh version of the app comes
from or I can create a new Branch if I
want to make some changes here we know
I'm going to make some changes so let's
open a new Branch here the first thing I
need to do is select the branch I want
to create a branch off and in this case
I'm going to start with the main branch
and then I'm going to create a new
branch called
Stefan for my
changes it's going to check out the code
as we can see here all the code from
this extension is here I can go back to
the page inspector and do the explore
page in vs code to get to that specific
page or I can just find the the page
here and do my changes
for example here I would do
mandatory maybe
false so far so good I can go to my
GitHub changes and I can add a good
description commit that and publish the
branch create a pull request and then
feed it back into my source management
system and then we can get the whole
pipelines running and the thing deployed
to production I can of course also test
it out first if I want to do that just
by pressing F5
and then I'll get it deployed to my
sandbox and I can now see that my change
is in
effect so from the extension management
page here you now have access to the
source even though you cannot download
it of course only if you have access to
this skop repo so you don't need to
change the resource protection policies
if you already have access to the
resource to the source code in giop algo
for GitHub automatically populates this
information in extensions that are built
using Al go for GitHub so that means
that there are other extensions out
there that we can see and yes we have
access to some we have access to a
specific one called system application
which is stored in the BC apps repo
again here I can go to this app and see
that is actually from the BC apps we can
see down here in the hint and we can see
a specific commit it also means that I
can actually open the source nvs code
here so let's try that
this time around it's going to ask me
again if I want to open the repository I
want to clone a new version of the
repository or here I want to reopen the
repository this reopen is here because I
actually have done this before so by
doing this I don't need to clone it yet
again I'll
reopen and it's going to get me to the
repo that I previously cloned and I can
start looking into the code here maybe
figure out why there's an error and then
maybe also suggest changes by creating a
new branch and doing a poll request to
BC
apps so while you now can see the the
repo information in the extension
management page you may or may not have
access to that repo so you need to take
care of that first you need to make sure
that the the repo that you're cloning
you have access to otherwise you'll get
an error when cloning it you can go
explore your extension management and
find other applications that may have
the source information set and if you
have access to those repost you can go
clone them and expect that
sauce that is it for this feature I hope
you enjoyed watching thank you very much